hey everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist
in this short video I am going to show
you how you can import folder structures
right from a Microsoft Excel sheet
now if you use Microsoft Excel
to basically build your automated tests
then you can import your tree structure
directly into Tosca Commander so you
don't have to manually build all the
folders uh in to your component folder
in Tosca you can directly use whatever
you have in Microsoft Excel or what you
have already built in Microsoft Excel
and write it State into your task
component folder right so let's see how
we can do this
the only thing to keep in mind is that
you need to follow some requirements in
order to import your t-structure from
Microsoft Excel to Tosca
so uh let's see an example of what we
are going to import right so I have got
this particular folder structure okay so
this is from the vehicle insurance
website we have used this many times uh
to automate some test cases and this is
how my test case folder structure should
look like okay so I've got uh the main
folder and then there are subfolders
like preprocessing process and post
processing so this is following the best
practices to build our test cases and
then inside pre-processing we have open
application uh in inside the process we
have the actual uh test case Okay so the
flow of the application like uh
selecting vehicle data and then entering
vehicle data entering personal data
entering insurance data and then
choosing the product and doing the
premium calculation and then checking
the premiums like insurance tax
according to the payment okay and then
in post processing uh we have the close
application okay so you can see in this
structure we have got different levels
of uh folders right and these folders
will contain different test cases right
so this is the folder structure I want
to build in Tosca
so instead of going to Tosca and
building this folders one by one which
will take some time right so if I've got
this or if I want to build this in Excel
quickly and then directly import it uh
into my Tosca right so I can do that uh
by just uh having a structure like this
okay so the minimum requirements uh you
need to fulfill when you are building
your Excel right or if you want to
import this tree structure from Excel to
Tosca uh the objects which you are
building they should be hierarchically
structured okay in columns from left to
right okay so you can see there is a
hierarchy here so the vehicle insurance
offer so this is the parent object
inside this we have got preprocessing
and you can see this is uh in First
Column and pre-processing process and
post processing so these are in the
second column okay and then
there is another subfolder
which is open application similarly
there are other folders here as well so
these are in the third column and
finally the final folder is in the
fourth column okay so this is the
hierarchical structure which you need to
follow in Excel the way you want to
build it in your Tosca uh component
folder okay so you need to put it in
different columns okay or or rows and
that should be from left to right okay
so objects of the same hierarchical
level are in the same column okay so you
can see here these are all the same
levels these uh objects are at the same
level right so they are present in just
one column and similarly for this they
are present in another column so you
need to make sure that objects at the
same level have to be in the same column
also you need to make sure that there
can be only one value per row okay so
you cannot have two values in the same
row so make sure of that and the
structure should have uh less than 15
levels okay so you cannot have more than
15 levels uh in the structure right so
these are the things you need to take
care of when you are trying to import
your tree structure from Microsoft Excel
to Tosca okay now coming to the actual
steps on how to import this particular
structure which I built on Excel sheet
into my Tosca Commander right so for
this what we need to do uh first come
here and select all the rows which you
have in your structure and click on
control plus C to copy it okay and then
go back to Tosca Commander here I can
export it into any folder but it's best
practice to basically build a component
folder okay
so I will name it vehicle or I will name
it import
from Excel
okay and then inside this right uh when
you right click on this you will see
there is an option called create folder
structure you can also use shortcuts
like Ctrl n and Ctrl s okay and that
will basically
um build a structure from the copied
cells of your Excel sheet okay so if I
right click on this and I click on this
create structure you will see the
structure will be automatically created
inside this folder okay so you can
create it inside any folder you can
create a test case folder and then put
this inside that or you can put it
inside a component folder you can do it
anywhere you like
now if I want to see all my folders
beneath this level then I can do a
expand all here and you will see that
all the folders which were present in
our Excel sheet structure has been
created here okay with the hierarchical
structure which we had okay with all the
levels so you can see here there is
process reprocessing and post processing
obviously they are not in the right
order but you can always change them
okay
okay so that's how you can create any
folder structure or basically import
your folder structure right from your
Excel sheets so if you are building or
if you're maintaining your test cases
before Tosca in some Excel sheet uh you
can build a structure like this and put
it together or import it into your Tosca
project okay so this could be useful in
some cases
but I just wanted to show you in this
short video how you can do this
so that's all for this video I hope you
enjoyed it and you learned something new
today uh there are lots more videos
coming up so uh do remember to subscribe
to our Channel and until the next video
keep watching and keep learning Tosca at
our channel to a script